JONAH I.

Programmer, Graphic Designer and an Educator

AJAAH JONAH INUSAH

168, Nii Oglie Rd. Saki Tema, Kpone Katamanso

(+233) 556262646

jonahinusah@gmail.com/jonahinusah@icloud.com

Profile

I am a dedicated and versatile programmer with expertise in software development, full-stack web development, and graphics design. I have a strong passion for educating people and enhancing student performance. With a comprehensive understanding of teaching and class management, I am capable of effectively conveying complex information. I possess excellent proficiency in Microsoft Office suites, Internet applications, and presentation skills. I am a team player with outstanding interpersonal and communication skills. Furthermore, I am cooperative, humble, and capable of working under pressure to meet deadlines with minimal supervision.

Skills

TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS

Programming Tools: Eclipse, NetBeans, MS Visual Studio, Xampp, Wamp, Visual Studio Code, JetBrains (IntelliJ and Pycham), Android studio.

Design Tools: Adobe Photoshop, and CorelDRAW

Database Management: SQL Server 2014 and Date, MS Access, MS Excel, MySQL

Languages: PHP, Java, HTML, CSS, C++, C, C#, JavaScript, Python, Veb.net

Model View Controller: Laravel

Research and Planning: Identifying Problems, Gathering Information, Developing

Evaluations, Calculating Results

Cloud-Based Technologies: AWS, GCP, Git, Github, Ms Office 365

SOFT SKILLS: Communication, Teamwork, Flexibility, Confidence, Problem-Solving, and Self-management

Experience

Ghana Armed Forces / National Service Personnel

NOVEMBER 2022 - Present, LA DEDE KOTOPON

Networked computers and performed troubleshooting, Configured routers and conducted programming tasks and Undertook hardware fixing and installations.

Akim State University College / E-Liberian

SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2020, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Networked computers and resolved technical issues and Configured routers and provided support to students in the library.

Akim State University College / Account Clerk SEPTEMBER 2021 - MARCH 2022, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Collected fees and accurately recorded financial transactions, Prepared receipts and performed other administrative duties as required.

The Prince of Zion Academy / Teacher (Science and Mathematics)

SEPTEMBER 2015 - AUGUST 2018, KAKASUNAKA NO.2

Managed classroom activities, improving student performance through effective teaching methods, Assumed the role of secretary, organizing meetings, writing minutes, and coordinating events.

Education

Akim State University College / Bsc Computer Science

AUGUST 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2022, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Studied various subjects including Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Database Systems, Programming Languages, Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computer Graphics, Web Development, Human-Computer Interaction, Software Engineering, and Computer Security.

Chemu Senior High / General Science

SEPTEMBER 2012 - JUNE 2015, AKIM ODA-ASENE

Focused on Biology, Chemistry, Physics, Elective Mathematics, and other subjects.

Interest

in Teaching, Typing, and Designing, Computer Networking, Database Management, Hardware Repairs, Computer programming, Analyzing and Solving problems through observations, watching documentaries and Researching, Love listening to music.

Reference

Jonathan Ocansey Elford/ Headmaster and English Teacher The Prince of Zion Academy/Kakasunaka no.2- MICHEL CAMP-TEMA 0244658468

Nana Asare-Djikinu/ Vice Principal/ Director/ Business Law Lecturer/ Akim State University College 0242256070/ 0207163787

Mr Philip Darko/ Registrar and Lecturer/ Akim State University College 0542864518